Guide to the Darrin Zammit Lupi photojournalism archive, 2004-2017 RL.11613
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Malta Detention, 2004-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints; 12.57 Gigabytes 1821 files (147 tiff, 1646 jpeg, 20 png, 8 pdf)
  - TIFF images (electronic files), 2004-2013; 147 files (.tif); 12 GB
    - Hands and feet out, 2012 July 17; Original file id: _JM97371 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0183)
      An African illegal immigrant's feet dangle through the window bars at the Safi detention centre in Safi, outside Valletta, July 17, 2012. Illegal immigrants arriving on the island of Malta are detained for up to 18 months, a policy which the United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR) has said urgently needs a comprehensive review following the death of a Malian immigrant while in custody last month, according to local media. There are currently around 1000 immigrants being held in detention, according to government officials. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Bridget Ezukuse, 2012 August 18; Original file id: _MG_8412 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0184)
      Bridget Ezukuse, a Nigerian newly-arrived immigrant whose husband drowned before he could be rescued on Wednesday sits crying in a common room at the Lyster Barracks detention centre in Hal Far, outside Valletta, August 18, 2012. Some 1200 immigrants have landed on the Mediterranean island of Malta since January. They face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Iyahen Sunday, 2012 August 18; Original file id: _JM92601 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0185)
      Iyahen Sunday, a Nigerian would-be immigrant sits in a common room at the Lyster Barracks detention centre in Hal Far, outside Valletta, August 18, 2012. Some 1200 immigrants have landed on the Mediterranean island of Malta since January. They face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Corridor behind bars, 2012 August 18; Original file id: _MG_8439 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0186)
      African would-be immigrants stand in a corridor at the Lyster Barracks detention centre in Hal Far, outside Valletta, August 18, 2012. Some 1200 immigrants have landed on the Mediterranean island of Malta since January. They face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Waiting to see the doctor, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _MG_1096 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0187)
      Newly-arrived would-be immigrants wait to see a medical doctor at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Looking through the bars, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _ZL_9981 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0188)
      A Somali would-be immigrant looks through a barred gates at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Migrant with Detention Service officer, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _MG_1104 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0189)
      A newly-arrived Somali would-be immigrant, accompanied by a Detention Service officer, reaches out to a friend at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Old friends reunited, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _MG_1112 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0190)
      A newly arrived Somali would-be immigrant (C) is greeted by an old friend at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 10, 2013. The two women said they had been held in detention together in Libya for seven months. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Towel headscarf, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _ZL_9998 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0191)
      A would-be immigrant stands against a wall at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Mother with her children, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _ZL_0006 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0192)
      An Eritrean would-be immigrant and her children stand at a corridor in the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Families behind bars, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _MG_1123 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0193)
      Eritrean would-be immigrants stand in a corridor at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Migrant poses for portrait, 2013 July 10; Original file id: _ZL_0014 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0194)
      A would-be immigrant poses for a picture at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants in Hal Far, outside Valletta, July 10, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Bed frame, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _MG_1639 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0195)
      A bunk bed metal frame is seen outside a window at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Tight squeeze, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4917 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0196)
      A Somali would-be immigrant stands at a window at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Fenced in, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4927 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0197)
      A would-be immigrant looks through a fence at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Watching from beyond the fence at Safi detention centre, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _MG_1648 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0198)
      Would-be immigrants walk in a courtyard at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Standng in the dormitory (1), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4976 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0199)
      Would-be immigrants stand in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Standng in the dormitory (2), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4983 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0200)
    - On beds, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4985 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0201)
      Would-be immigrants sit in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Migrants at Safi detention centre, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_4990 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0202)
      Would-be immigrants sit in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Volleyball, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5002 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0203)
      Would-be immigrants play volleyball in a courtyard at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta, July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Looking outside (1), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5016 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0204)
      A would-be immigrant looks through a barred gate at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta, July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Waiting …, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5063 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0205)
      Would-be immigrants stand near an Armed Forces of Malta guard (2nd R) at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta, July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - No more football, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5082 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0206)
      An old soccer ball is caught in a razor wire fence at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Somali women, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5095 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0207)
      Somali would-be immigrants sit in a common room at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Holy pictures (2), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _MG_1699 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0208)
      An Eritrean would-be immigrant touches pictures depicting Jesus Christ while on her bunk bed at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Two women, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5126 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0209)
      Would-be immigrants lie on a bunk bed at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Phone call from Zone C, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _MG_1710 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0210)
      An Eritrean would-be immigrant talks on the phone at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Women in garbasaars (shawls), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5140 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0211)
      Somali women sit in a common room at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Walking to her dormitory, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5158 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0212)
      A Somali would-be immigrant walks to her dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Peeking into the corridor, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5169 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0213)
      A Somali would-be immigrant peeks out of her dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Malta will be given concrete assistance by the European Commission to return failed asylum seekers to their country of origin, the government has announced. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Somali woman peeks out of dormitory, 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5182 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0214)
      A Somali would-be immigrant peeks out of her dormitory at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Somali woman by the window (1), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5197 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0215)
      A Somali would-be immigrant stands by a window at the Lyster barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 250 detainees, in Hal Far, outside Valletta July 19, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Somali woman by the window (2), 2013 July 19; Original file id: _ZL_5206 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0216)
    - Standng in the dormitory (3), 2013 August 6; Original file id: _ZL_0342 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0217)
      Would-be immigrants stand in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants which currently holds around 600 detainees in Safi, outside Valletta, August 6, 2013. Would-be immigrants who land in Malta face mandatory detention which can last for 18 months but figures show nearly half are allowed out sooner, following the granting of refugee status or humanitarian protection, according to official sources. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Waiting to see the doctor (2), 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_2959 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0218)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants wait for medical examinations at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Reading up on asylum-seeking procedures, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3130 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0219)
      A Sub-Saharan African migrant reads a booklet about asylum-seeking procedures at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Italy will seek an overhaul of European asylum policies and emergency action to handle a crisis that has seen tens of thousands of African migrants arrive in Sicily and Malta and hundreds of deaths, Prime Minister Enrico Letta said on Tuesday. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Relaxing in dormitory, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _ZL_3147 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0220)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants relax in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Under watchful eyes, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_2989 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0221)
      An Armed Forces of Malta soldier watches as Sub-Saharan African migrants relax in their dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013. Photo: Darrin Zammit Lupi
    - Sleeping migrants, 2013 October 22; Original file id: _MG_3002 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0005, Image-file RL.11613-TIFF-0222)